# ROCKSON CHANG

GitHub: rocksonchang

ResearchGate: Rockson Chang Webpage: rocksonchang.github.io Institut d'Optique Graduate School 2, Avenue Augustin Fresnel 91127 PALAISEAU CEDEX (office) +33 1 64 53 33 45 (mobile) +33 6 78 92 96 99 chang.rockson@gmail.com

Physicist specializing in quantum, many-body systems of ultracold gases. Motivated by complex problems demanding technical yet creative solutions. Experienced with research-oriented programming in Python and Matlab for numerical simulation, user interfaces, data treatment and analysis. Strong project management and communication skills with 10 years of experience working in small-to-mid sized teams.

## Personal details

Nationality: Canadian.

Date of Birth: July  $10^{th}$ , 1982.

## Education

## 2006-2013 Doctor of Philosophy.

Department of Physics, University of Toronto, Canada

Thesis: Exploring matter-wave dynamics with a Bose-Einstein condensate

Supervisor: Aephraim M. Steinberg

#### 2005-2006 Master of Science.

Department of Physics, University of Toronto, Canada

Thesis: An optical-dipole trap for experiments with Bose-Einstein condensates

Supervisor: Aephraim M. Steinberg

#### 2001-2005 Bachelor of Engineering Science.

Major in Engineering Physics with first class honours, Queen's University, Canada 4th year thesis: Single-electron transistors

## Selected Research Experience

#### 2013- Post-doctoral fellow.

present Atom Optics group, Laboratoire Charles Fabry, l'Institut d'Optique Graduate School, France Researcher studying many-body correlations that arise in strongly-interacting ultracold gases.

#### 2005-2013 Research assistant.

Department of Physics, University of Toronto, Canada

Experimental research studying matter-wave dynamics with Bose-Einstein condensates.

### 2005 Research assistant, NSERC undergraduate research award.

D-Wave Systems, Canada

Design of a cold-finger for mounting a prototype for a 4-qubit, superconducting quantum computer.

### Refereed Publications

- 2016 R. Chang et al. Momentum-resolved observation of quantum depletion in an interacting Bose gas, In preparation.
- 2015 F. Nogrette et al. Characterization of a detector chain using a FPGA-based time-to-digital converter to reconstruct the three-dimensional coordinates of single particles at high flux, Review of Scientific Instruments, 86, 113105, 19 November 2015. Pre-print: arXiv:1507.03816.
- 2015 Q. Bouton et al. Fast production of Bose-Einstein condensates of metastable helium, Physical Review A, **91**, 061402(R), 9 June 2015. Pre-print: arXiv:1504.06197.
- 2014 R. Chang et al. Three-dimensional laser cooling at the Doppler limit, Physical Review A, **90**, 063407, 1 December 2014. Pre-print: arXiv:1409.2519v2. Selected as an Editor's suggestion.

- 2014 A. Hayat et al. Enhanced coherence between condensates formed resonantly at different times, Optics Express, 22, pp. 30559-30570, 1 December 2014.
- 2014 R. Chang et al. Observing the onset of effective mass, Physical Review Letters, 112, 170404, 2 May 2014. Pre-print: arXiv:1303.1139. See also Phys.org's feature story on the work.
- 2013 R. Chang et al. Observation of transient momentum-space interference during scattering of a condensate from an optical barrier, Physical Review A, 88, 053634, 26 November 2013. Pre-print: arXiv:1303.1137.

## Selected Awards

- 2012 Van Krandendonk teaching award, for teaching assistants at the University of Toronto.
- 2008 Ontario Centre for Excellence, travel award to CASTU Frontiers of Degenerate Gases in Beijing.
- 2007-2010 University of Toronto Fellowship, for Doctoral studies.
- 2005-2006 E. F. Burton Fellowship, for Master's studies.
  - 2005 NSERC Industrial undergraduate research award with D-Wave Systems.

## Selected Teaching Experience

- 2014-2015 Lab demonstrator, Master 2 « Optique, Matière à Paris », Université Paris Sud. Tutorial and lab demonstration on an ultracold atoms experiment for Master students. Teaching in French.
  - 2013 **Teaching Assistant**, PHY335 - Quantum Mechanics for ECE, University of Toronto. Tutorial leader for introduction to quantum mechanics for electrical and computer engineering students.
- 2011-2012 **Teaching Assistant**, PHY224/324 Practical Physics, University of Toronto. Demonstrator for intermediate level-undergraduate labs for physics specialist students. Python based.

## Computer competencies

Python: extensive numerical simulation, image treatment and analysis, development of GUIs with Tkinter, experience with iPython notebook.

Matlab: numerical simulation, image treatment and analysis, development of GUIs with GUIDE, extensive experience with data treatment and analysis, figure generation for scientific communication.

Additional programming languages: Maple, Labview, HTML

Technical design software: OSLO, SPICE, Solidworks

Office software: LATEX, Microsoft Office Suite, Apache Open Office

Some of my projects can be found on GitHub (username: rocksonchang)

## Languages

Native English speaker.

International French as a second language – professional working proficiency (ILR scale).

### Personal Interests

Sports: Avid climber, with a love of both sport climbing and bouldering.

Currently The Looking Glass War, John le Carré

reading: